Ashwin Chalaka

408-834-3724 | San Francisco Bay Area ashwin.chalaka@gmail.com

LinkedIn **GitHub** github.com/ashwinchalaka

linkedin.com/in/ashwinchalaka

Full-stack web/mobile developer and software engineer with 1+ years of experience. Proficient in numerous programming languages, modern frameworks, and development tools. Quickly learns new technologies. Schooled in clean object-oriented design and easy-to-follow documentation. Most notably accomplished an enterprise web solution within 4 months as a technical and organizational lead.

Education

San Jose State University **B.S. Software Engineering** (2nd year / Sophomore)

Foothill-De Anza College Computer Science for transfer (2017 - 2020), GPA: 3.66

> **Oregon State University Industrial Engineering** (2014 - 2017)

Experience

STEM-Away.Inc, Santa Clara, CA and remote-work - Project Lead and Full Stack Developer

Jul 2019 - Oct 2019

- Controlled the product development life cycle of the STEM-Away Career Statistic Tool and successfully launched within 4 months
- Resolved a process bottleneck that immediately advanced the team from project planning to the prototyping stage
- Engineered ...
 - a Python-Django MVC architecture and deployed to Google Cloud that brought the project to life
 - a script to process API data through validation and filtration into a PostgreSQL database which eliminated need to manually verify the data
 - an admin tool inside of the Python-Django application to securely edit previous entries into the database

Coding Dojo, San Jose, CA - Web & Mobile Developer Accelerator Student

Jul 2018 - Nov 2018

- Exceeded 1,000 hours of onsite training in web/mobile development
- Earned job-ready proficiency in 3 full-stack technologies and a double black-belt certification

Foothill College Pass the Torch, Los Altos Hills, CA - Calculus Teaching Assistant (T.A.) and Math Leader (Tutor) Spring 2018 - June 2019

- Completed 40+ hours of outreach and mentorship training with evaluation
- Recommended by my Vector Calculus teacher for both positions

Oregon State University Client Services, Corvallis, OR - Service Desk Associate and Student Technician Jan 2016 - May 2016

- Documented and organized all customer requests for technical assistance and servicing hardware
- Trained and became proficient in diagnosing and servicing laptop, mobile, and desktop computers

Technical Skills — all in 3 years

- Formal Classes

- Computer Science:
 - Object Oriented Design, Assembly Language, Data structures, Algorithms, Discrete Math, Calculus, Physics
- Software development:
 - Java

Coding Dojo, On the Job, and Self Taught

- Web development:
 - MEAN Stack, Python, JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, MVC, AWS EC2 Deployment, Google Cloud, Modularization
- Frontend:
 - AngularJS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Design, The Box Model, AJAX, Figma,
 Adobe Photoshop, GIMP
- Backend:
 - Django, NodeJs, Express, Flask, Session, Bcrypt,
- Database:
 - SQL, noSQL, mySQL, SQLite, ORMs, MongoDB, Mongoose, Models, Relational Tables
- Mobile development:
 - Swift (iOS), Xcode, Auto Layout, CoreData, CoreMotion, CoreLocation, MapKit, UIKit,
 AVFoundation
- API:
 - JSON, RESTful, Postman
- Other Developer tools:
 - GitHub, Microsoft VS Code, IntelliJ, Eclipse, Sublime Text, Asana, Slack

Organizational Leadership

- In School

- Trained and then worked as a notetaker and tutor for registered disabled, disadvantaged, and struggling students, see <u>LinkedIn</u> for full list of prior jobs
- STEM-Away see endorsement here
 - Detailed project organization and communication of technical information, as seen here
 - Partnered with supervisor to build a full team and personally trained entry-level members
 - Coordinated remote and in-person meetings between mentees and mentors and delegated tasks to all team members